Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we're
going shopping to date English Pod.
That's right today we are going to the
store because we want to return a product.
So maybe the product that we bought had
some problem and we want our money back.
That's right, so
let's take a listen to
today's dialogue and we'll be back in a
moment to talk more about what's going on.
Hi, I would like to return this TV.
Sure.
Do you have a receipt?
Yeah, here you go.
Actually I also want
to return this keyboard.
Okay, may I ask what the reason
for returning these products is?
The TV flickers a lot
when I am watching a
movie and at times the
image is not very clear.
I see. And what about the keyboard?
I spilled some coffee
on it and now it will work.
I'm sorry man, but we can only
exchange or refund defective products.
We cannot take responsibility
for misuse or damages.
Fine.
I don't know why they make
these things so delicate anyways.
All right, we're back
so now let's take a look
at some of those keywords
on language takeaway.
So we've got a great bunch
of words for you here today.
The first three are nouns
and then afterwards
we've got a couple of
adjectives to describe
those nouns, but first up
we have the word receipt.
That's right, so we want
to return the television
and the worker there asks
us if we have the receipt.
Okay, a receipt is a
small piece of paper that
you receive from a clerk or a
server after you buy something.
So if I buy a TV, I will
have this small piece
of paper that says that
I paid $500 for the TV.
That's right.
So usually they will
ask you for the receipt
to see when you bought the product and
if you bought the product at that store.
That's right.
So the receipt has all
sorts of information,
date, time, method of
payments cost, all those things.
Right.
And it's very important if you
ever want to return something.
Now later on in the dialogue, the character
explains why he wants to return the TV.
Now Marco, why does he want to do that?
Well, he has a problem
with the TV when he's
watching a movie, basically
the image is not very clear.
So this is the keyword image.
So image can mean a
couple of different things.
You might hear the
word image to mean a
photograph or a picture
like on a computer, but
in this case, the image is how well you
can see the images on TV, the things on TV.
That's right.
So on TV, it's like you're
seeing many, many
images all at once or
very rapidly together.
So maybe if you can't see clearly, you
say that the image is not clear on the TV.
All right.
And so if it's fuzzy like there's
gray and black, the image is not clear.
You can also say that, you
know, I really like my new TV.
The image is very clear.
That's right.
Okay.
And not only are we returning a TV,
but we're also returning a keyboard.
All right.
A key board, a key is
something that you can push.
But a keyboard is this thing that you
use with your computer to type words.
That's right.
So many of you who are using the website as
we speak are using a keyboard and a mouse.
So these are probably
one of the two most
well-known objects when
you're using a computer.
That's right.
And keyboards come in
many different shapes and sizes.
You can buy French keyboards
and Russian keyboards.
So keyboard is the
general word for this tool.
Okay.
So we're returning the keyboard and the
clerk explains that we can only return it if
it is defective, if the
product is defective.
All right.
So this is one of those adjectives
I talked about a minute ago.
Adjectives describe things.
So my keyboard is defective
or this TV is defective.
That means it doesn't work.
That's right.
So we have a defective product.
It's not working properly.
It has some problem.
And well, the guy was
complaining that he didn't
understand why these things,
like the keyboard are so delicate.
All right.
Delicate is something
you might see written on
the side of a box when
you receive a package.
Something that is
delicate breaks very easily.
That's right.
So you have to handle with care.
So for example, glass is very delicate.
It can break easily.
All right.
Glass is delicate, but stones.
A big rock.
That's not delicate.
That's right.
All right.
So that's all we have
for language takeaway.
Let's review everything
and listen to our dialogue.
Hi.
I would like to return this TV.
Sure.
Do you have a receipt?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Actually, I also want
to return this keyboard.
OK.
May I ask what the reason
for returning these products is?
The TV flickers a lot when
I am watching a movie.
And at times, the image is not very clear.
I see.
And what about the keyboard?
I spilled some coffee on
it, and now it will work.
I'm sorry, ma'am, but we can only
exchange a refund-effective products.
We cannot take responsibility
for misuse or damages.
Fine.
I don't know why they make
these things so delicate anyways.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look
at a couple of phrases
we've picked out for to
be exact on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
The first verb we have
today here in fluency builder
is the main verb in
today's dialogue to return.
So I would like to return this TV.
OK, so when you want
to give back a product,
you don't say I want to give
back or anything like this.
You say I want to return this product.
Well, it's not just giving back.
It's giving back and
getting your money back.
That's right.
So to return means that
you bring back the product
and the store will give
you back your money.
That's right.
And he wanted to
return the TV, as we
mentioned, because the
image was not very clear.
But he also mentioned
that the TV flickers a lot.
So what is this to flicker?
To flicker is another verb.
And flicker is something
that the things with
light do, the light
flickers, the TV flickers.
It means the light comes
on and off, on and off.
So dark light, dark light.
It's not very steady.
It's not like there's light, dark.
And so this is very annoying
when you're watching
TV because it goes
light, dark, light, dark.
And it's hard to see what's happening.
Exactly.
So it's basically just imagine someone is
turning on and off the light all the time.
That's the same thing
that's happening with the TV.
It flickers.
Exactly.
Or like when a light bulb in your lamp,
when a light bulb is dying, it flickers.
That's right.
All right, so we wanted to
actually return these goods.
And the clerk explained that we can exchange
or we can refund defective products.
Okay, these are two important verbs.
Exchange means to trade
one thing for another.
Right.
So when I go to a foreign
country, I exchange money, right?
I can exchange Japanese
yen for American dollars.
But at a store, like an electronic store,
I can exchange my TV that I don't like
or maybe a really good mp3
player or something like that.
So that's what happens usually if maybe
your TV is broken or it had some problem.
You exchange it for a new one, right?
So, but maybe you don't
want the TV anymore.
Maybe you change your mind.
So you want to get a refund.
So refund, you hear this word,
fund, it has to do with money.
A refund means that the store
will give you all your money back.
So if I refund my TV, I
give my TV to the store.
The store gives me $500 or
whatever the money for the TV was.
And I can buy anything else anywhere else.
That's right.
So this is what happens
when you get a refund,
very different from
exchanging the goods.
And finally, the clerk
explained that they
cannot take responsibility
for misuse or damages.
So remember this as a phrase.
This is really important
to take responsibility.
It means that if something goes
wrong, you will take responsibility for it.
You will handle it.
All right, so for example,
the store says that it
can't take responsibility
if something is broken.
That means that they
won't pay you back money.
That's right.
So if you buy a TV and
you accidentally get it wet
or you get water inside and
this is why it gets damaged,
then the store cannot take
responsibility for this damage.
Or you could say the other way around,
you could say if you're at the office
and you make a mistake on our report,
you say listen boss, I'm really sorry.
I take full responsibility
for this mistake.
You can punish me or you
can make me do it again.
But I take responsibility
means that I say it's my fault.
- Right, your guilty.
All right, so that's all we
have for Fluency Builder.
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time
and we can review
everything we've just learned.
(gentle music)
- Hi, I would like to return this TV.
- Sure, do you have a receipt?
- Yeah, here you go.
Actually, I also want
to return this keyboard.
- Okay, may I ask what the reason
for returning these products is?
- The TV flickers a lot
when I am watching a
movie and at times the
image is not very clear.
- I see, and what about the keyboard?
- I spelled some coffee
on it and now it won't work.
- I'm sorry, ma'am, but we can only
exchange a refund defective products.
We cannot take responsibility
for misuse or damages.
- Fine, I don't know why they make
these things so delicate anyways.
(gentle music)
- So returning goods is a very useful thing
if you maybe bought a
TV at a department store
or an electronic store, then
you would want to return it
if you had some problems.
Now, how easy or difficult is it to do?
Because in theory, in the
dialogue, it seems like it's really easy.
- It depends on the store, of course.
So some stores make it easier to do this.
Some stores make it harder.
I can tell you in most
stores, if you don't
have a receipt, it's
probably very difficult.
- Really?
- Yes, but a lot of stores
have something else
that they sell you or give
you when you buy something.
It's called a warranty.
And this is something
that will help protect you
if you take the TV home
and you have a problem.
And that means that they will
come fix it or they will give you
a new one without any
questions about what happened.
- Now, not only can you
return goods such as TVs,
electronics, or maybe
clothes, but in some cases,
also things that you buy at the
supermarket, like maybe chicken.
I've heard that maybe
sometimes you buy chicken
and you open it up that
same day and it's gone bad.
- Really?
I've never had that experience,
but I think it makes sense.
It depends where you buy it, of course.
- Right, obviously at a supermarket
and you show the receipt
or maybe milk, maybe that's
gone bad sometimes or yogurt.
- Well, because they probably
shouldn't sell it if it's bad.
- Exactly.
- So if you tell them that they still
do bad milk, okay, how do you know?
- Exactly.
- So that's called an exchange.
You would exchange the
bad one for the good one.
- Right, you wouldn't get your money back.
- No, maybe, maybe not, maybe.
- All right, so that's all
the time we have for today,
but this is actually a
very interesting topic
because it has to do a
lot with customer service.
So let us know what
your experience is with
customer service with
returning something.
Is it very easy, very difficult?
Maybe some stores
don't even accept returns.
They say, "Once you buy
it, you cannot return it.
" - All sales final.
- Yeah, exactly.
- So let us know our refunds or
exchanges common where you come from
and have you ever had a
bad experience where you
bought something and it
didn't work when you got home?
Let us know our website is EnglishPod.com.
- All right, we'll see you guys there.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)